today
is barge day i am dedicating this entire
wow this entire episode to the barge and
the first thing that i'm gonna do
is give you some kind of idea of how
long i have been
chopping
wood not the most exciting thing but two
hours of chopping wood and i have a
feeble amount yeah check check this out
really quick time lapse not not even
gonna not even gonna give you any music
it's that's how unimportant and boring
this was chopping wood but check it out
i've got i didn't even get a full
shulker box of some of the bits
like two hours and you know i kind of
regret getting into the log business to
be honest with you i don't have an auto
log producer or the whatever they what
are they called
wood farms i don't have a wood farm
but i have got enough stock to go ahead
and yeah there's a raid in my base
and i can't find it i don't know where
it is i've i don't know how it happened
i don't know where they are
i've had a look around
nothing oh
you that is more than what are they all
there
i think that i think this is the most
bizarre raid i've ever seen i think
there is they're all there
they're having a party out there having
a rooftop party
that's amazing that is amazing
well i wasn't expecting that right well
raids take a long time to fight so we're
going to forget about that we're going
to go and stock up the barge but like i
was saying
regret getting into the log business
let's stock all of this up believe it or
not logs are one of my biggest sellers
okay so stocked up the barge with logs
but we're not actually gonna be focusing
on this barge we're gonna be making
something that you might have seen on my
community post oh my goodness there's
someone behind me and i also have a
proximity chat on so we might be able to
hear scar
you do have proximity oh my goodness no
that scared me oh
you you waited
i was like batman up in the
raptors of awkward town
you waited just long enough for me to
question whether proximity chat was
working so scar and i aren't actually
using discord right now we're just using
a minecraft mod and the further i get
away uh tech i think right
quiet
there you go hello
scar
can you hear me hello hello
amazing
hello
uh and i just can you explain what's
going on with your face
um
uh no i can't explain it other than that
it's beautiful yeah you know what i
don't even want to know while you're
here actually can i are you still
selling this tower because i would uh
i'd still love it oh the big one yeah
you put signs and i tore them all down
um so i forgot you how much did you want
to buy it for
i don't remember how much did you buy it
for
oh you know
200 diamond blocks
i don't believe that for a second
i don't actually remember go on then how
much do you want um okay all right
it's not about the diamonds it's about
something else come with me come with me
up here up on threads
is that there is a ginormous
and i mean ginormous beethoven's face up
there it's beautiful it's what no it's
disgusting oh
all right right so the stipulation with
buying this property would be that that
needs to be changed out or removed
entirely bonus points if it's of me
angela but not a requirement on that
phone but it needs to be removed and
i'll sell it for
blocks 35 you drive you're mr money back
this building will be great for your
entrepreneur-ness i don't think that's a
word but just think just think of the
prestige the barge industries will have
by owning the best building in aqua town
done
and the billboard uh i kind of like the
billboard
if i give you 5000 blocks back will you
will you remove it yes i will salt
i am i am the greatest negotiator
okay so
that's now my
tower
but all i have to do is remove the
billboard remove the billboard and it is
a hundred percent sealed in yours okay
done shake on it how do we shake
ouch
i lost all my hearts
the proximity mod just made that so much
better
like watches
watches actually great
oh wow you did you did it you did it you
did it okay okay okay you did eat it
[Music]
[Laughter]
oh that's awesome oh man
i can't even talk to scar now because
he's nowhere near me
[Music]
this is how you do business in aqua town
hello i'm back oh
oh man
i got your stuff i
i've never had to do that before i
literally just i just had to wait about
five minutes before doing this next clip
because my cat was purring too loudly
into the microphone i just just had to
ask her for politely can you stop
purring
okay so now what we're going to do
is work on barge hq now a while ago i
put a poll on the community post on
youtube asking which one did you prefer
a or b
and i've got to say it's probably about
it it was a close call
yeah 99 of you said b
99 that's such a huge amount and also
000 comments maybe even more by now
crazy these posts are mad okay so i am
actually
going to agree with you that's the one
that i want to build b i want this to be
very open airy and glassy and here is
scar so what we're going to do is we're
going to get into a time lapse of
building an enormous barge hq and i
think i might actually make it a little
bit taller than my original design
one it can kind of match what's here and
two it looks like there's plans to build
something on this corner plot so i want
it to stick over the top so i might need
to make this quite a bit taller than i
initially thought but that's okay
there's
there's no one enforcing vertical height
restrictions is there
desk of the building officer of vertical
enforcement hmm
well that's just inviting something to
happen isn't it so what how does this
work welcome to the office of the
building of vertical enforcement above
why didn't they make it aqua
aqua office of building no wait aqua
building officer vertical enforcement
above you've missed such a trick there
okay
uh what is the building limit what is
the building limit impulse this is the
worst document i've ever seen it says it
says that there's a maximum height limit
but you haven't said what it is and i
can buy more
that's just that's asking for trouble
i've had a look at this video and it
turns out the answer is 90 blocks 90
blocks is the limit for aqua town
apparently and you have to buy more well
forget that it's not happening so why
don't we just go out of our way to be
really annoying and make a build that's
91 blocks tall hmm oh maybe even taller
i don't know right anyway let's get into
this time lapse and make ourselves a big
old
tower of barge
let's
go sorry green
[Music]
check it out we have one
completed
barge hq
tower
let's get a bit of a better angle on
this because
well it's probably not a huge shock it's
uh probably in the thumbnail and i
already asked you which design i wanted
but does it remind you of any particular
building
if you said big ben you're wrong because
big ben is the bell but it does resemble
elizabeth tower in london and that is
very much the inspiration for this
particular build and you know what i
think it actually fits inside of aqua
town
very very nicely
now i've been thinking about this guy
here
the big smiling b-dubs and i think that
it's kind of a shame
to get rid of it
but it is part of the deal
of collecting the deed for this tower so
i'm just gonna clarify something really
quick with scar
scar can you confirm that all i have to
do is not have b-dubs on the billboard i
just need i don't know whether he wants
me to remove the entire billboard or if
i can just remove the b-dubs
yes
fool okay so i have a few ideas and
we're gonna have to experiment to see
what works
first of all let's take a screenshot so
we remember exactly what this looks like
i want to know
if b dubs face will fit inside the barge
hq
oh that's mighty cursed that is so
cursed b dubs with no eyes
they say the eyes are the windows to the
soul
but it would appear that
b-dubs eyes are the window to a rather
empty building okay let's go and have a
look and see if this will fit so i've
got all the bits of b-dubs eyes which i
never thought i'd say in an episode of
hermitcraft
it's going to be a bit of a weird one
today isn't it you know talking about
b-dubs his eyes i can immediately say i
don't think this is going to work
because that's
that's his eyes and i can't do much more
than
that in this small space
[Laughter]
it looks like yeah it looks like we got
a very happy
barge hq and a very soulless b dubs
no no i don't think that's going to work
for me unfortunately
so
i
and also i don't really want to actually
remove the billboard so according to
scar all i need to do is remove b-dubs
from this so i have a feeling that
there's
i think there's a work around here
so what i'm thinking
is just to save myself having to fill in
because this billboard isn't actually on
top of the building it is the building
if i remove the billboard i'd have to
make an entire side of the building but
i think it would be much better
if we just refilled and changed up some
of the colors and the palette of this
build
and i think you might be guessing where
it's going as i change this blue to red
if you haven't figured it out yet i
guess you know where it's going
boom
exactly what scar
didn't want
okay so we've replaced b-dubs with a
giant smiling green which i've got to
say
doesn't quite deliver the smile that b
dubs this skin does it it is a feeble
imitation if you ask me however
it's still it's still pretty cool what
we are going to do is we're not going to
actually say goodbye to b-dubs skin
because i would like to include it on
the barge i specifically asked if it was
just about removing b-dubs from the
billboard scar never said i couldn't put
it anywhere else so the plan here is to
create a bit of a flying b-dubs hanging
from barge hq i don't care if it's got
nothing to do with the barge i just
really like seeing b-dubs is smile into
my soul face
and take a look at that
b-dubs is back
just
hanging around
i think this works pretty well you can
see b-dubs just just peeking over the
top of all of the buildings i don't
think it detracts too much from barge hq
especially if you look at it from this
angle which is
i'll be honest this is the open area at
the moment so this is kind of where
everyone's hanging out so it doesn't
interrupt the skyline and then as you're
just walking through the town
b-dubs i don't i can't let that big
smiley boy down
so that's my project for aqua town
complete but what's going to go on the
inside
well
up here i hope to make my barge hq
office now i've been putting a great
deal of thought on how to get up and
down this rather large tower and i've
been doing some explosive testing on my
server to see if it's possible and i
believe
that oh my goodness no wonder i ran out
of materials i forgot to say forgot to
take down the eyeballs
whoops
um that that explains a lot i was like
where is where have all these bits of
wool gone
so what i'm thinking is we have a
basically a tnt dispensing square right
in the middle you turn it on you stand
here as long as you're on full health
it'll launch you
all the way up hopefully to the top uh
hopefully maybe just that layer and then
you've got to walk the rest of the way
and then up here we want our actual
meeting room and we get a lovely view
of b dubs his face
so this is going to be perfect but what
is barge hq actually going to do well
it's not just a place for my office
what this is actually going to be is one
last money-making venture for the barge
so the barge has been great it has made
me a very wealthy person on the
hermitcraft server it
basically it sells just about everything
that you would need but it particularly
focuses on grindy things such as hello
sand and gravel is my biggest money
maker but it also includes a bunch of
other stuff and now including logs which
i seriously regret getting into and a
bunch of other stuff that's a pain in
the neck to get your hands on and we've
tried our best to venture out into
different things we started selling
boxes of stuff which haven't actually
sold too much but we also tried things
like barge quest which were extremely
successful so my next venture is going
to be some sort of mini game but it's uh
i don't think it's been done on the
hermitcraft server before so i'm not
actually going to spoil it because it's
going to take me a little while to make
and by a little while i mean a very long
while this is not not something that i
need to get into lightly and it's
certainly going to prevent me from
making the back of the mansion for at
least another couple of weeks so that's
why we're definitely gonna do it okay so
what we're gonna have is our launcher up
to the top and the start of a barge
related mini game which i think will
prove to be reasonably popular
we've had a bit of a disaster here i'll
i'll be honest with you i i got really
angry because
i've set up this and
i wasn't recording i'm not annoyed that
it blew up i'm actually annoyed that i
wasn't recording because i was like
i was just i was just like idly doing
this and i i clicked the button it
released the tnt if you don't know this
is a launcher so basically you stand on
here it launches tnt and up you go
that's at least that's the plan and i
watched as one tnt just slowly slid
into the bubble elevator and it just
went
bang everything everything went lost all
the glass and what was really annoying i
lost about half my shulker boxes i don't
think it was anything too much but
anyway enough of my
woes
what i need to do is give this a proper
test so we got a splash potion of turtle
master to give me the proper resistance
there should be some tnt in there
and uh
let's just see if this works
oh no not again again again
okay
i don't think this works that's that's
not far off what happened last time
that's not far off what happened last
time
okay so
i'm thinking the bubble elevator isn't
the way to go
so when i say that this was tested on my
server i mean it definitely worked on my
server
but i didn't quite anticipate that i'd
have to edit the design a little bit
uh so this this has not gone
particularly well
let's just do a botch job for now okay
should we try this again
this time i'm going to use my i thought
i was going to be clever by using soul
sand to kind of propel me so forget it
this time i'm going to put a slab there
and
in theory
all i got to do
is just bounce on it like this
that
i don't think this works does it i feel
a bit silly as well sitting in the pool
of failure there must i'm pretty sure
this worked
whoa
well at least this time it doesn't
self-destruct let's try again because i
think i had it
let's go three two one
no
it
it launched me but not far enough
so let's try adding two more okay
we're gonna test this
test number two
and go
all right doesn't launch you straight up
which is a bit annoying right
last chance
ah
they don't all
they need to explode at the same time
[Music]
okay come on
oh no
i ran out of potions
guys i think i've lost all my items i
think i've lost all my netherright gear
oh
we're about to find out i have a sneaky
suspicion
[Music]
i can't cry in minecraft but if if i
could i would be crying
this was a terrible idea
it's completely reliant on turtle master
potions i i don't have time right now to
put everything back together the way it
was
i do have some spare oh i have some
spare tools
okay
a lit i've i have a few spare tools
and i have some spare elytra i've got
one lonely nether
nether i inger it's okay i've i've got
enough lint in my pocket to be able to
put put my life back together now
i i don't have time for anything else in
this episode now it's been slightly
spoiled by my
shoddy red this redstone has killed me
my redstone has not only killed me
it's it's it's it's taken everything
from me you know what i think
i think the the end of this episode i'm
just gonna listen to some music and
think about what i've done
[Music]
so
you